Waleed Bin Humran - Assoc CIPD L5

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia ■ +966-599888088 ■ w.humran@yahoo.com

OBJECTIVE

A highly versatile management professional with 20+ years of exceptional track record in strategic planning, human capital management, acquiring, training, development and quality management, with added proficiency in project management, management of operations, seeking an executive profile to contribute in achievement of tangible organizational benefits.

KEY SKILLS

- Human Capital development, Leadership, Team Building, Motivation & Communication
- Strategic Planning, Talent acquisition, Training and Development, Project LCM, Process Mapping
- Client Relationship Management, Market Research, Competitor Analysis
- Project Risk, Opportunity & Procurement Management, Safety, Health & Environment, Service Quality
- Compliance Review, Revenue Generation, Management Reporting
- Standardized Policies and Procedures, Coordination and Development
- Design, Process Mapping, KPIs, Operating and Maintenance
- Analytical Ability, work under pressure proficiency, Critical Thinking, Decision Maker and Problem Solver
- Service Level Agreements, Contractual Negotiations, Employee Performance Management
- Computer Related Skills: ERBs, MS Office and Internet Usage

CAREER GLIMPSE

Bazy Co.

July 2021 - Present

Al-Nasser Group

Feb 2020 - May 2021

HR Consultant

June 2014 – Present

Alamiya for Media & Advertising Co.

Oct 2018 – Sep 2019

Emdadat International Investment Co.

Oct 2015 - Nov 2016

Nov 2017 - Oct 2018

Hyoon Company Limited

Oct 2008 – June 2014

Saudi Telecom Company

BAE Systems Saudi Development & Training

Jan 1998 – Oct 2008

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE DETAILS

Human Resources & Admin Director, Bazy Co.

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

July 2021 – Present

Key Responsibilities:

- Hands on the recruitment & selection processes, appointment operations and follow up the implementation of recruitment plans to determine the requirements of human resources, according to the selection and appointment system, fulfilling organizational recruiting needs.
- Identify and approve the estimated budget for the human resources and support services department annually, in coordination with the Finance Department.
- To provide the company requirements through his work team such as contracting with medical insurance and auto insurance companies and property appropriate for each year by requesting offers, make necessary studies and comparisons and formation of a committee to take the suitable decision.
- Ensure that the salaries and bonuses system is applied efficiently.
- Take necessary action regarding the implementation of the company's policies with respect to the administrative staff promotions or bonuses or addition of other functions and duties to the JD cards of a particular job.
- Make sure the extent of matching company's human resources activities, policies and procedures with the provisions of the law and governmental actions, according to the Saudi labor law and make sure not to violate any of them in coordination with the responsible Legal Affairs.
- Conduct studies that will establish a motivational environment within the company and work on creating the spirit of loyalty and love for the company.
- Assess the training needs of the company's employees and approval of the training plan.
- Supervision of the control procedures for employees working hours and their different kinds of vacations through
 the daily attendance records and the departures and vacations form, and calculation of the balances in addition to
 overseeing the operations of the preparation of payroll and monthly wages in accordance with the approved
 procedures.
- Preparation of periodic reports on the activities and achievements of the department and submitted to the CEO.

Waleed Bin Humran - Assoc CIPD L5

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia ■ +966-599888088 ■ w.humran@yahoo.com

HR Consultant Riyadh, Saudi Arabia June 2014 - Present

Key Responsibilities:

- Advising management on the administration of human resources policies and procedures
- Translation of organization strategies, policies and objectives into plans so as to include internal development and increase productivity and to participate in its implementation through coordination with subordinates.
- Initiating and leading human resource programs and projects
- Serving as internal consultants by analyzing a company's current HR programs and recommending solutions
- Developing, revising, and implementing HR policies and procedures
- Ensuring HR programs and services are in compliance with established policies and procedures and government laws and regulations
- Devise plans and techniques to drive change and culture management
- Assisting with the development and coordination of recommended changes regarding workflow
- Review systems and processes and make modifications to address issues
- Conducting audits of HR activities to ensure compliance
- Presenting training sessions related to specific HR programs

HR & SS Director, Al-Nasser Group

Feb 2020 - May 2021

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Head of Human Resources, Alamiya for Media and Advertising Co.

Oct 2018 - Sep 2019

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

HR & SS Manager, Emdadat International Investment Co.

Nov 2017 - Oct 2018

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

General Manager, Hyoon Training & Consultancy

Oct 2015 - Nov 2016

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

HR Project Manager at BAE Systems Saudi Development & Training

April 2014 - June 2014

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

HR Planning & Reporting Manager at BAE Systems Saudi Development & Training

Oct 2012 - April 2014

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

HR Senior Training Coordinator at BAE Systems Saudi Development & Training

Oct 2009 - Oct 2012

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

HR L&D Training Coordinator at BAE Systems Saudi Development & Training

Oct 2008 - Oct 2009

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

STC in various positions and roles

Jan 1998 - Oct 2008

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

EDUCATION

Chartered Institute of Personal Development - CIPD L5

Aug 2021

Oakwood International Academy

Telecommunication College Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

July 1997

Intermediate University Certificate in the specialty of operating systems and maintenance of EWSD Siemens Exchanges

Training and Certifications:

- Key Performance Indicators "KPIs" HR Management Training Institute: Royati Training, Jan 2020
- Certified Corporate Governance
 Training Institute: FAACT Academy, August 2019
- Society for Human Resource Management (SHRM SCP)
 Training Institute: Morgan International May 2015
- Project Time & Cost Management
 Training Institute: Atlantic Management Center Inc, Aug 2009
- Hay Job Evaluation Training Training Institute: Hay Group, Oct 2013
- Microsoft Project 2003
 Training Institute: Al Khaleej Training & Education Oct 2012

Waleed Bin Humran - Assoc CIPD L5

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia ■ +966-599888088 ■ w.humran@yahoo.com

- FAA Level 2 Award in Emergency First Aid at Work qualification Training Institute: NUCO Training, May 2014
- Integrity in Business Dealings
 Training Institute: BAE Systems training portal, April 2013
- Middle Managers, Performance Enhanced Coaching (PEC)
 Training Institute: Emerge Development Consultancy, Sept 2012
- Bottom Line Project Management Foundations Training Institute: PCI Global Inc, March 2012
- Bottom Line Business Analysis Foundation Training Institute: PCI Global Inc, February 2012
- Project HR & Communications Management
 Training Institute: Atlantic Management Center Inc, July 2011
- Project Management Framework and Integration
 Training Institute: Atlantic Management Center Inc, Nov 2010
- Mastering People Management & Team Leadership Training Institute: GLOMACS, Jan 2010

- Middle Managers, Leading Transformational Change (LTC)
 Training Institute: Emerge Development Consultancy, Sept 2012
- Bottom Line Project Leadership
 Training Institute: PCI Global Inc, March 2012
- Bottom Line Business Analysis, Use Cases & Business Modeling Training Institute: PCI Global Inc Date Attended: Feb 2012
- Bottom Line Business Analysis, High Quality Business Req. Training Institute: PCI Global Inc Date Attended: Feb 2012
- Project Risk, Opportunity & Procurement Management Training Institute: Atlantic Management Center Inc, Oct 2011
- Managing Service Quality & Customer Satisfaction Training Institute: EuroMaTech, Dec 2010
- Hay Group Job Analysis Training
 Training Institute: Hay Group, July 2010
- Project Scope & Quality Management
 Training Institute: Atlantic Management Center Inc, June 2009

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- · Gender: Male
- Nationality: Saudi
- Marital Status: Married
- Languages: expert level English & native Arabic
- LinkedIn Profile: Waleed Bin Humran